A Guide to the Pamela Webb Architectural Collection, 1950-2009
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Pamela Webb Architectural Collection, 1950-2009
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2009-099
66 containers; 85.9 cubic feet
The Pamela Webb Architectural Collection contains the professional files, architectural drawings, artwork, and photographs of an architect working primarily in Portland, Oregon, during the last quarter of the twentieth century.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Pamela Webb Architectural Collection was donated to Special Collections in 2009.
Biographical Information
Born in 1943 in Cheyenne, Wyoming, Pamela Webb was an artist, architect, businesswoman, curator, and member of the Portland, Oregon community. Webb earned a degree from Harvard University in Anthropology in 1966; but, later studied architecture and graduated from the Oregon School of Design's first class in 1985.
Some of Webb's significant architectural projects in Oregon include: the Warms Springs Early Childhood learning Center, the Eastbank Esplanade, and the Austen Row multifamily housing project—for which Webb won the 1991 Metropolitan Homebuilders' Best Attached Home designation.
Webb also embarked on several architecturally inspired business endeavors, such as SiteStudy.com (a field study course for architects) and "Webb Grid" (a Mylar grid for pinbar overlay system, for which Webb sought a patent).
In addition to her architectural projects, Webb also served as a board member of the American Institute of Architects Oregon Chapter and as the director of the Harvard University Club of Oregon from 1986 to 1989.
Before becoming an architect, Webb co-founded a successful artists' cooperative called the Blackfish Gallery and worked as a high school art teacher from 1972 to 1976. She also acted as a licensed general contractor in Portland from 1977 to 1985. Webb eventually continued her interest in art through designing jewelry and fused-glass windows and plates.
Pamela Webb died in October 2008 at the age of 65.
Scope and Content
The Pamela Webb Architectural Collection contains the professional files, architectural drawings, artwork, and photographs of an architect working primarily in Portland, Oregon. Materials date largely from the latter quarter of the twentieth century, but extend into the early twenty-first century. Professional files include information about Webb's career (resumes, portfolios, etc), money-making endeavors, correspondence, press coverage, community involvement, proposal bids, and architectural projects.
Architectural renderings within the collection appear in different mediums—in diazo prints, on thin wax paper, and on white copy paper. These renderings document Webb's architectural projects (including her student work).
Significant projects include: Eastbank Esplanade, Forest Heights residential community, Austen Row attached homes, Warm Springs Early Childhood Learning Center, and Marian Abram's Children's Wing in Mittleman Jewish Community Center. The collection's photographs illustrate the construction and finished products of many of Webb's project designs.
Webb's provided artwork depicts a variety of subjects—from human forms to abstract designs to building ideas. In addition to drawings on paper, some of Webb's artwork is etched in metal or Plexiglas. Multiple sketchbooks also appear within the collection.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged first by material type and subsequently by subject matter. Webb's professional business files remain separated from her pictures, oversized architectural drawings, and artwork. The Professional Papers and Files are divided into the following subseries: Career Overview, Educational/Scholastic Papers, Professional Organizations and Boards, Community Involvement, Press Coverage, Business Ventures/Development Projects, Internal Business Documents, Proposals, and Projects. Within the aforementioned categories, files appear alphabetically with the exeption of the "miscellaneous" or introductory folders that sometimes appear at the beginning of a subseries. Photographs, artwork, and oversized drawings maintain their own series—items within these sections echo the subseries outlined in Webb's Professional/Papers and Files when applicable.
Note: Bracketed dates within the contents list indicate that the dated material was not created by Pamela Webb.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Additional photographs of Forest Heights construction and houses may be found in the Pamela Webb Collection, Org. Lot 1219, Oregon Historical Society Research Library.
Contents List
- Professional Papers and Files
  - Career Overview
    - Supplemental Information [Supplied by Jay Margulies], undated (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Miniature Dossier, c. 2001 (Box-folder 1:2)
    - Resumes and Professional Biography, 1990, undated (Box-folder 1:3)
      Includes a brochure featuring a blurb on Webb's background in anthropology and architecture.
    - "Nostalgia—Pam," 1986-1991 (Box-folder 1:4)
    - Miscellaneous Personal / Professional Correspondence, undated (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Educational/Scholastic Papers
    - Transcripts, 1982, 1987, undated (Box-folder 1:6)
    - Essay [Student Work], undated (Box-folder 1:7)
    - Oregon Committee for the Humanities Grant Application, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 1:8)
      Completed for the Oregon School of Design.
    - Oregon School of Design Catalog, Portland, OR, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 1:9)
    - Oregon School of Design—Remodel Workshop, 1986 (Box-folder 1:10)
    - Oregon School of Design—"Signs of Aalto," 1984 (Box-folder 1:11)
    - Oregon School of Design—Thesis Proposal, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Professional Organizations and Boards
    - AIA, 1991-1999 (Box-folder 1:13)
    - AIA Awards—Submissions, 1992 (Box-folder 1:14)
    - AIA Contracts, 1993-2000 (Box-folder 1:15)
    - AIA Lecture Series, 2002 (Box-folder 1:16)
    - Harvard Club of Oregon, 2001 (Box-folder 1:17)
    - Intern-Architect Development Program, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 1:18)
    - "NCARB Official Stuff" [National Council of Architectural Registration Boards], 1989-1990 (Box-folder 1:19)
    - Oregon and Washington State Boards of Registration, 1987 (Box-folder 1:20)
    - Oregon State Board of Architect Examiners, 1991 (Box-folder 1:21)
    - Oregon State Board of Architect Examiners, 1999-2002 (Box-folder 1:22)
    - Oregon State Board of Architect Examiners—House Bill 3268, 1991 (Box-folder 1:23)
    - Oregon State Board of Architect Examiners—License, 1995 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - Community Involvement
    - Blackfish Gallery, Portland, OR, 2009 (Box-folder 1:25)
      Webb was the founding director of Blackfish Gallery—a quasi co-operative association of local Portland artists.
    - Fairmount Hotel—L & C Expo, Portland, OR 1980-1981 (Box-folder 1:16)
      Webb was instrumental in getting this building on the National Register of Historic Places.
    - Gordon House, Wilsonville, OR, 2001 (Box-folder 1:27)
    - Sapporo Sister Cities Association—Portland Pavillion Plaque, Sappporo, Japan 1990-1991 (Box-folder 1:28)
    - Sapporo Sister City Board, Portland, OR, 1989 (Box-folder 1:29)
  - Press Coverage
    - Press Releases and Press Coverage, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 1:30)
    - Daily Jounal of Commerce—Architecture Review, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 1:31)
    - Downtowner Article, Portland, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 1:32)
  - Business Ventures / Development Projects
    - Pam's Business Ideas, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 1:33)
    - "Wheeling & Dealing," 1990 (Box-folder 1:34)
      Concerns attracting overseas development deals.
    - 12 Berkeley Street, Cambridge, MA, undated (Box-folder 1:35)
    - 465 NE Olney Ave., Bend, OR, 1999 (Box-folder 1:36)
    - 2101 NE 8th, Portland, OR, 1979 (Box-folder 1:37)
    - 2552-2556 NW Savier St., Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 1:38)
    - 2725 SE 34th, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 1:39)
    - 4033 SE Milwaukie and Rhine, Portland, OR, undated (Box-folder 1:40)
    - Ballard, Walter M., Correspondence, 1992 (Box-folder 1:41)
    - Brooten Family Property, Tillamook County, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 1:42)
      Webb collected information concerning the purchase of a parcel of land.
    - Columbia-Willamette, Beaverton, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 1:43)
    - Director / Sellwood, Portland, OR, undated (Box-folder 1:44)
    - House Portrait Certificate, undated (Box-folder 1:45)
    - KIT—Keep in Touch 1997 (Box-folder 1:46)
      Webb proposed a networking website for groups.
    - Lloyd Center 8plex, Portland, OR, undated (Box-folder 1:47)
      Business venture to go into partnership and buy a rental property.
    - "Main Street Mansion," Portland, OR, 1979 (Box-folder 1:48)
    - Punch-Board, 2000 (Box-folder 1:49)
    - Scheller / Webb Townhouse Project [66th Street], Portland, OR, 2001 (Box-folder 1:51-52)
    - Shiffman / Garner, 1991 (Box-folder 1:52)
    - Webb & Co.—Financial, 1987 (Box-folder 1:53)
    - Webb & Co.—"Webb Grid," 1987 (Box-folder 1:54)
    - Travel Ed / Site Study.com
      - AIA Contracts, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 1:55)
      - AIA Monthly Ad, 2000 (Box-folder 1:56)
      - Assignment Agreement, 2004 (Box-folder 1:57)
      - Business Plan, 1997 (Box-folder 1:58)
      - Completed Programs, 2002 (Box-folder 1:59)
      - Completed Programs—Sent to University of Oregon, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 1:60)
      - Completed Studies, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 1:61-62)
      - Federal EIN [Federal Employer Identification Number], 2000 (Box-folder 1:63)
      - Legal, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 1:64)
      - Partnership Return, 1997 (Box-folder 1:65)
      - Partnership Return, 1998 (Box-folder 1:66)
      - Partnership Return, 1999 (Box-folder 1:67)
      - Partnership Return, 2000 (Box-folder 1:68)
      - Receivables, 1997 (Box-folder 1:69)
      - Review, 1997 (Box-folder 1:70)
      - "Studying a Building with Architects' Eyes," 1998 (Box-folder 1:71)
      - "Studying a City with Architects' Eyes," 1998 (Box-folder 1:72)
      - Vendor—"A," 1999 (Box-folder 1:73)
      - Vendor—"K," 1998 (Box-folder 1:74)
      - Vendor—""W, X, Y, Z," 1998 (Box-folder 1:75)
  - Internal Business Documents
    - Bills for Pamela Webb, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 1:76)
    - Business Cards, undated (Box-folder 1:77)
    - Business Graphics and Letterheads, undated (Box-folder 2:1-2)
      Includes Title Block Graphics.
    - Business Licenses, 1991, 2002 (Box-folder 2:3)
    - Invoices, 1992 (Box-folder 2:4)
    - Invoices & Accounts Receivable, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 2:5)
    - Leases, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 2:6)
    - Logs, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 2:7)
      Includes information about the dates of clients and also project numbers.
    - Miscellaneous B, 1991 (Box-folder 2:8)
    - Miscellaneous T, 1991 (Box-folder 2:9)
    - Miscellaneous A, B, C, 1993 (Box-folder 2:10)
    - Miscellaneous S, T, U, V, 1993 (Box-folder 2:11)
    - Miscellaneous E, 2002 (Box-folder 2:12)
    - Miscellaneous Government [County] Forms, undated (Box-folder 2:13)
    - Miscellaneous Notes and Specifications, undated (Box-folder 2:14)
    - Miscellaneous Product / Appliance Information, undated (Box-folder 2:15)
    - Obsolete Job Files, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 2:16)
    - Office of Minority, Women, and Emerging Small Business, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 2:17)
    - Pamela Webb.com, 1999-2001 (Box-folder 2:18)
    - Pamela Webb Logos, 1994 (Oversize 17:2)
    - Pricing Guidelines, undated (Box-folder 2:19)
    - Product Numbers, 1991 (Box-folder 2:20)
    - Receipts, 1998-2002 (Box-folder 2:21)
    - Schedule of Design Services, c. 1993 (Box-folder 2:22)
    - Timesheet, 1993 (Box-folder 2:23)
    - Webb / Merryman, 1992 (Box-folder 2:24)
    - Webb / Merryman Logo, etc., undated (Box-folder 2:25)
  - Proposals
    - Rejected Proposals, 1998 (Box-folder 2:26)
    - Admiral Theater Proposal, Bremerton, WA, 1991 (Box-folder 2:27)
    - Beth Israel Center for Jewish Life Proposal, Eugene, OR, 1998 (Box-folder 2:28)
    - Clackamas County Proposal, Clackamas County, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 2:29)
    - Creative Strategies for Change Proposal, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 2:30)
    - Digital Equiptment Corporation, Tualatin, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 2:31)
    - East Bank Master Plan Proposal, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 2:32)
    - East Bank Proposal Packet, Portland, OR, undated (Box-folder 2:33)
    - Florence All Events Center Proposal, Florence, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 2:34)
    - General Services Proposal, Portland, OR, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 2:35)
      This later becomes the project titled "Auditor's Office."
    - Goose Hollow Station Proposal, Portland, OR, 1994 (Box-folder 2:36)
    - Housing Authority of Portland Design Competition Proposal, Portland, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 2:37)
    - "Indian Trails" Proposal, Warm Springs, OR, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 2:38)
    - Kennedy School Master Plan Proposal, Portland, OR, 1994 (Box-folder 2:39)
    - Lake Oswego Golf Course Proposal, Lake Oswego, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 2:40)
    - Marion County Family Court Proposal, Salem, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 2:41)
    - Martin Luther King Jr. Blvd Development Opportunity Strategy Project Proposal, Portland, OR 1993 (Box-folder 2:42)
    - Mittleman Jewish Community Center Proposal, Portland, OR, 1992, 1994 (Box-folder 2:43-44)
      Project later becomes Marian Abrams Children's Wing.
    - Oregon Village Proposal, Japan, undated (Box-folder 2:45)
    - Portland Community College Proposal, Portland, OR, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 2:46-47)
    - Regional Design Images Proposal, 1993 (Box-folder 2:48)
    - Rothchild Building Proposal, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 2:49)
    - Scappoose Public Library Proposal, Scappoose, OR, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 2:50)
    - Scappoose Senior Center Proposal, Scappoose, OR, 1994 (Box-folder 2:51)
    - Sylvan Heights Club Proposal, Portland, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 2:52)
    - Temple Beth Israel Proposal, Eugene, OR, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 2:53)
    - Temple Beth Shalom Proposal, Salem, OR, 2000 (Box-folder 2:54)
    - Vancouver Clinic OB / GYN Proposal, Vancouver, WA, 1993 (Box-folder 2:55)
    - Warrenton / Astoria Head Start Center Proposal, Warrenton, OR, 1994 (Box-folder 2:56)
  - Projects
    - Miscellaneous Designs and Drawings for Relatives, undated (Box-folder 2:57)
    - Miscellaneous Unknown / Untitled Drawings, undated (Folder 2:58)
    - Abrams / Ramirez Renovations, Portland, OR, 1996 (Box-folder 2:59)
    - Acadia Properties, Bend, OR, 2000 (Box-folder 2:60)
    - Accent Eyewear, Hillsboro, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 2:61)
      The drawings for Accent Eyewear and Murryhill Eye Care were intermingled by Webb and often lack distinquishing titles.
    - Accent Eyewear—Financial, Hillsboro, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 2:62)
    - Administrative Services Building Extension, Corvallis, OR, undated (Box-folder 2:63)
      Small 8x10 inch copies of a building extension drawing.
    - Adult Corrections Restitution Center, Corvallis, OR, 1999 (Box-folder 2:64)
    - Andresen Project, Portland, OR, 1994 (Box-folder 2:65)
    - Andresen Project—Financial, Portland, OR, 1994 (Box-folder 2:66)
    - Aspenridge, Vancouver, WA, 1992 (Box-folder 2:67)
    - Auditor's Office, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 3:1)
    - Auditor's Office—General Information, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 3:2)
    - Auditor's Office—Administration, Portland, OR 1993 (Box-folder 3:3)
    - Auditor's Office—Assessments / Liens, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 3:4)
    - Auditor's Office—Council / Contracts, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 3:5)
    - Auditor's Office—Records Management, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 3:6)
    - Austen Row, Portland, OR, 1990 (Box-folder 3:7-9)
    - Austen Row—Project Communication, Portland, OR, 1990 (Box-folder 3:10)
    - Austen Row—Project Information, Portland, OR, 1990 (Box-folder 3:11)
    - Balderas Renovation, 2000 (Box-folder 3:12)
    - Barnes / Kinsey Renovation, Portland, OR, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 3:13)
    - Beckett / Stephens Renovation, West Linn, OR, 2001 (Box-folder 3:14)
    - Beckham House, Lake Oswego, OR, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 3:15)
    - Beling / Dougherty Offices, Las Vegas, NV 1995 (Box-folder 3:16)
    - Bella and Mark's Kitchen, 2001 (Box-folder 3:17)
    - Benson Project, undated (Box-folder 3:18)
    - Bentley Lighting, Portland, OR, 1998-1999 (Box-folder 3:19-20)
    - Beverly Woodstove, 1980 (Box-folder 3:21)
    - Bissonette Project, 1979 (Box-folder 3:22)
    - Bloombaum Project, undated (Box-folder 3:23)
    - Boguchi Project, 1978 (Box-folder 3:24)
    - Broken Top (Cascade Highlands), 1990 (Box-folder 3:25)
    - Broken Top (Cascade Highlands)—Builder Program, c. 1990 (Box-folder 3:26)
    - Broken Top (Cascade Highlands)—Sales Office, 1991 (Box-folder 3:27)
    - Burns / Palmer Carpet, Portland, OR, undated (Box-folder 3:28)
    - Cable Village, Portland, OR, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 3:29-30)
    - Cable Village—Carter Case, Portland, OR, 1995 (Box-folder 3:31)
    - Cable Village—Financial, Portland, OR, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 3:32)
    - Cable Village—Joanne Jene, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 3:33)
    - The Capes, Tillamook County, OR, 1990 (Box-folder 3:34)
    - Cardmill Project, undated (Box-folder 3:35)
    - Carson Hot Springs Resort—Carter Case, Carson, WA, 1995 (Box-folder 3:36)
    - Center for Airport Management, Portland, OR 1995 (Box-folder 3:37)
    - Centurion Homes—Alternate Elevations, 1991 (Box-folder 3:38)
    - Charbonneau [AKA French Prairie], 1987 (Box-folder 3:39)
    - Chown Showroom, Portland, OR, 1996-2000 (Box-folder 3:40)
    - Christy Renovation, Portland, OR, 1998 (Box-folder 3:41)
    - Cirrany Residence, Portland, OR, 1994 (Box-folder 3:42)
    - Claremont Alternate Elevations, Portland, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 3:43)
    - Claremont Alternate Elevations—George Marshall Company, Portland, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 3:44)
    - Claremont Clubhouse, Portland, OR, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 3:45)
    - Claremont Clubhouse—Publications, Portland, OR, c. 1991-1992 (Box-folder 3:46)
    - Clark Project, Portland, OR, 2000 (Box-folder 3:47)
    - Cody Garden Room and Big Garage, Portland, OR, 1995 (Box-folder 3:48)
    - Cogan Residence, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 3:49)
    - Cogan Flood Repairs, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 3:50)
    - Cole Project, 1996 (Box-folder 3:51)
    - Constant Improvements, Gresham, OR, 1995 (Box-folder 3:52)
    - Corliss Project, 1978 (Box-folder 3:53)
    - County Cork Public House, Portland, OR, 1999 (Box-folder 3:54)
    - Curtis Project, undated (Box-folder 3:55)
    - Darmohray Renovations, Portland, OR, 1998 (Box-folder 3:56)
    - Dart / Beaumont Home Office, Portland, OR, 2002 (Box-folder 3:57)
    - Didner Restaurant, Portland, OR, 1997 (Box-folder 3:58-59)
    - Du Charme Project, undated (Box-folder 3:60)
    - East Bank—Exposition, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 3:61)
    - East Bank—Financials, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 3:62)
    - East Bank—Master Plan, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 3:63; 4:1-7)
    - East Bank—Master Plan: Design 7.1 Guidelines, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 4:8)
    - East Bank—Master Plan Draft, Portland, OR, 1994 (Box-folder 4:9)
    - East Bank—Master Plan Final Draft, Portland, OR, 1994 (Box-folder 4:10)
    - East Bank—Master Plan Guidelines, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 4:11-12)
    - East Bank—Schedules, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 4:13)
    - East Bank—Willamette Greenway Plan, Portland, OR, 1988 (Box-folder 4:14)
      Plan contains pertinent information concerning the site of the East Bank project.
    - Eclectic Arts, Portland, OR, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 4:15)
    - Eliot Row, Portland, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 4:16)
    - Epstein Project, Portland, OR, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 4:17)
    - Faherty Project, Beaverton, OR, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 4:18)
    - Florke Project, Portland, OR, 2001 (Box-folder 4:19)
    - Forest Heights, Portland, OR, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 4:20)
    - Forest Heights—Architectural, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 4:21)
    - Forest Heights—Architectural Forms, Portland, OR, undated (Box-folder 4:22)
    - Forest Heights—Architectural Review Committee, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 4:23-26)
    - Forest Heights—Architectural Review Committee: Agenda, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 4:27)
    - Forest Heights—Architectural Review Committee: Minutes, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 4:28)
    - Forest Heights—Architectural Review Committee: Miscellaneous, Portland, OR, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 5:1)
    - Forest Heights—Architectural Review Committee: Miscellaneous Correspondence, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 5:2)
    - Forest Heights—Carney Compliance to Forest Heights Board, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 5:3)
    - Forest Heights—Committee Correspondence, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 5:4)
    - Forest Heights—Declaration of Protective Covenants, Portland, OR, undated (Box-folder 5:5)
    - Forest Heights—Design Guidelines, Portland, OR, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 5:6-7)
    - Forest Heights—Design Review, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 5:8)
    - Forest Heights—Design Review: Application, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 5:9)
    - Forest Heights—Design Review: Communications, Portland, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 5:10)
    - Forest Heights—Design Review: Financials, Portland, OR, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 5:11)
    - Forest Heights—Design Review: "Hiring and Compensation," Portland, OR, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 5:12)
    - Forest Heights—Design Review: Logo, Portland, OR, undated (Box-folder 5:13)
    - Forest Heights—Design Review: "Memos, Forms, and Guidelines," Portland, OR 1992-1993 (Box-folder 5:14)
    - Forest Heights—Design Review: Miscellaneous, Portland, OR, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 5:15)
    - Forest Heights—George Marshall Company Sales and Marketing, Portland, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 5:16)
    - Forest Heights—Issues to Resolve, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 5:17)
    - Forest Heights—Mangan, Portland, OR, undated (Box-folder 5:18)
    - Forest Heights—Miscellaneous Architectural Notes, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 5:19)
    - Forest Heights—Miscellaneous Design, Portland, OR, 1991-1992 (Box-folder 5:20)
    - Forest Heights—Newsleter, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 5:21)
    - Forest Heights—Planning, Portland, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 5:22)
    - Forest Heights—Planning [FPE], Portland, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 5:23)
    - Forest Heights—Porter Correspondence, Portland, OR, c. 1994 (Box-folder 5:24)
    - Forest Heights—Pre-approved Home Designs, Portland, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 5:25-26)
      Includes a 1991 list of available lots and prices.
    - Forest Heights—"Recommendations for Image Enhancement," Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 5:27)
    - Forest Heights—Ridgeline [Lot 16, Block 5], Portland, OR, 1991 (Box-folder 5:28)
    - Forest Heights—Site Observation Notes, Portland, OR, 1992 (Box-folder 5:29)
    - Forest Heights—Site Visit Package, Portland, OR, undated (Box-folder 5:30)
    - Garrison Project, 1978 (Box-folder 5:31)
    - Garrison Bathroom, 1980 (Box-folder 5:32)
    - Gerton Project, 1991 (Box-folder 5:33)
    - Gibson Residence, Portland, OR, 2003-2004 (Box-folder 5:34)
    - Gisvold Project, undated (Box-folder 5:35)
    - Glasgow Project, Portland, OR, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 5:36-38)
    - Glosten Study, 1998 (Box-folder 5:39)
    - Goldschmidt Office, Portland, OR, 1993 (Box-folder 5:40)
    - Goose Hollow Station Area Planning, Portland, OR, 1994 (Box-folder 5:41)
    - Gordon Beach House, Surf Pines, OR, 2001 (Box-folder 5:42-43)
    - Gordon Beach House—Financial, Surf Pines, OR, 2000-2003 (Box-folder 5:44)
    - Gordon Kitchen, Portland, OR, 2008 (Box-folder 5:45)
    - Green / Holden Project, Portland, OR, c. 1984 (Box-folder 5:46)
    - Greenberg / Ritchie Project, Portland, OR, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 5:47-48; 6:1)